A Guide to the J. Hoge Tyler Family Collection, 1802-1956
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- SERIES II: PERSONAL PAPERS 1860-1925
  - Subseries A: Presbyterian Church 1866-1924
    - Printed materials, G-L (Box-folder 39-12)
      - Gilmer, Geo. H., "Home mission bulletin: Abingdon Presbytery" [1914]
      - Gordon, A. J., "Two men at a shot" [19--?]
    - Printed materials, M-O (Box-folder 40-1)
      - MacIntosh, Douglas Clyde, "Why I believe in immortality" 1925
      - The Missionary survey Jan 1924
    - Printed materials, Pa-Pm (Box-folder 40-2)
      - Peloubet, F. N., Peloubet's select notes on the international Sunday school lessons (improved uniform series: course for 1918) 1917
    - Printed materials, Pn-Pz (Box-folder 40-3)
      - Presbyterian Church in the U. S. Committee of Education, Annual report1883
      - Presbyterian Church in the U.S. Committee of Foreign Missions, Annual report1883
      - Presbyterian Church in the U.S. Executive Committee of Home Missions, Annual report1883
      - Presbyterian Church in the U.S. Executive Committee of Publication, Annual report... presented to the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Church in the United States1883
    - Printed materials, Q-Z (Box-folder 40-4)
      - The Quarterly register: organ of the Alliance of Reformed Churches Holding the Presbyterian System May 1897
      - Rall, Harris Franklin, "I believe" 1924
      - Signs of the times magazine Nov 1913
    - Miscellaneous 1866-1897, n.d. (Box-folder 40-5)
  - Subseries B: Genealogy 1876-1948
    - Incoming correspondence 1876-1924, n.d.
      - A-G (Box-folder 40-6)
      - H-Q (Box-folder 40-7)
      - R-Z, unidentified (Box-folder 40-8)
    - "Family genealogy, record and diary of James Hoge Tyler of Belle Hampton, Pulaski County, Virginia 1879, [typescript] (Box-folder 40-9)
    - "The Family of Hoge" n.d., [typescript][2 folders] (Box-folder 40-10)
    - Newspaper clippings 1895-1948, n.d. (Box-folder 40-11)
    - Miscellaneous 1900-1905 (Box-folder 40-12)
  - Subseries C: James Hoge Tyler General Correspondence 1860-1924
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - 1860-1879 (Box-folder 40-13)
      - 1880-1922 (Box-folder 41-1-5)
      - n.d., [3 folders] (Box-folder 41-6)
    - Incoming correspondence 1865-1924
      - A-C (Box-folder 41-7-12)
      - D-Mn (Box-folder 42-1-15)
      - Mo-Wa (Box-folder 43-1-16)
      - Wb-Z (Box-folder 44-1-3)
      - Unidentified, [2 folders] (Box-folder 44-4)
  - Suberies D: Sue Hammet Tyler Correspondence 1865-1927
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - 1867-1927, n.d. (Box-folder 44-5-6)
    - Incoming correspondence 1865-1926, n.d.
      - A-M (Box-folder 44-7-16)
      - N-Z, Unidentified (Box-folder 45-1-6)
      - Y-Z, Unidentified (Box-folder 45-7)
  - Subseries E: Scrapbooks 1871-1925
    - Scrapbook 1 1871-1893, n.d. (Box-folder 45-8)
    - Scrapbook 2 1894-1900, n.d. (Box-folder 45-9)
    - Scrapbook 3 1901-1924 (Box-folder 46-1)
    - Scrapbook with clippings about Tyler's death 1925, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 46-2)
    - Loose items from Scrapbook 1 1893, n.d. (Box-folder 46-3)
    - Loose items from Scrapbook 2 1899-1900, n.d. (Box-folder 46-4)
    - Loose items from Scrapbook 3 1882-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 46-5)
  - Subseries F: Printed Materials 1887-1929
    - A-H, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 46-6)
      - Boykin, James C., The Story of the Declaration of Independence1926
      - "Constitution of the legal fraternity of Phi Delta Phi" 1901
      - Cubasch, Woldemar, The Stanserhorn and the Stanserhorn Railway[189-?]
      - Hooper, Thomas W.Unconscious influence: an address delivered before the Union and Philanthropic Literary Societies1889
    - I-L (Box-folder 46-7)
      - In memoriam: John Warwick Daniel, born September 5, 1842; died June 29, 1910 [1910]
      - In memoriam [Sue Hammet Tyler] [1912]
      - "Independence Hall: a short history of the Independence Hall group of buildings" 1925
      - A List of the portraits and pieces of statuary in the Virginia State Library, with notes and illustrations 1920
    - M-R, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 46-8)
      - Mapping [1906]
      - A Message to the alumni of Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, N.J. 1918
      - The Rexall News Sep 1915
      - "Rhein-dampfschiffahrt: kolnische u. Dusseldorfer gesellschaft" [1896]
      - Richmond Apr 1929
    - S (Box-folder 46-9)
      - Shelburne, William J., Orations of William J. Shelburne, Jr., delivered by Milligan College, Tenn., and University of Va. with a brief sketch of his death1887
      - Society of the Army of the Potomac, Report of the thirty-first annual re-union at Fredericksburg, Va.1900
      - "Stanserhorn Bahn & Electr. Tramway: Stansstad-Stans" [189-?]
      - "Stansstad-stans-Stanserhorn-bahn" [1895]
    - T-Z (Box-folder 46-10)
      - The Treaty of peace between Spain and the United States [1898?]
      - Virginiana: catalogue no. 12 [19--]
      - The Waverly album: a photographic souvenir of the land of Scott [189-?]
      - "Western & Central Switzerland: Jura-Simplon railways: the largest and most picturesque railway in Switzerland" [1896]
    - Newspaper clippings 1893-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 47-1)
  - Subseries G: General Materials 1868-1926, n.d.
    - Third-party correspondence 1802-1913 (Box-folder 47-2)
    - Invitations
      - 1868-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 47-3-10)
    - Calling cards 1898-1925, n.d. (Box-folder 47-11)
    - Federal Food and Drug Administration 1917 (Box-folder 47-12)
    - Federal Food and Drug Administration 1918, [2 folders] (Box-folder 47-13)
    - Speech drafts n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 48-1)
    - Miscellaneous 1861-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 48-2-3)
- SERIES III: BUSINESS AND PERSONAL FINANCIAL PAPERS 1862-1923
  - Subseries A: Business Concerns 1882-1922
    - American National Life Insurance Company / Atlantic Insurance Company
      - 1906-1915 (Box-folder 48-4-5)
    - Belle Hampton Coal Company
      - Correspondence 1882-1887 (Box-folder 48-6)
      - Correspondence 1888-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 49-1-2)
      - Ledger no. 4 1884-1888 (Box-folder 49-3)
      - Ledger no. 5 1888-1891 (Box-folder 49-5)
      - Ledger no. 6 1892-1894 (Box-folder 49-5)
      - Miscellaneous 1883-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 50-1)
    - Belle Hampton store
      - Ledger no. 1 1886-1887 (Box-folder 50-2)
      - Ledger no. 2 1888-1890 (Box-folder 50-3)
      - Ledger [no. 3] (Box-folder 51-1)
      - Ledger no. 4 1892-1893 (Box-folder 51-2)
    - Radford Development Company
      - Correspondence 1890-1893 (Box-folder 51-3-7)
      - Correspondence 1894-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 52-1-2)
      - Letters of proxy 1890-1895 (Box-folder 52-3)
      - Receipts and account statements 1890-1914 (Box-folder 52-4-5)
      - Meeting reports and notes 1890-1895, n.d. (Box-folder 52-6)
      - Stock certificates 1890-1892, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 52-7)
      - Legal documents 1890-1912, n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 52-8)
      - Miscellaneous 1890-1899, n.d. (Box-folder 52-9)
    - Radford Trust Company 1902-1913 (Box-folder 52-10)
    - Southern Building and Loan Association 1891-1902, n.d. (Box-folder 52-11)
    - Virginia Agricultural Development Company 1891-1899, n.d. (Box-folder 52-12)
    - Virginia Mutual Building and Loan Association 1891-1893, n.d. (Box-folder 52-13)
  - Subseries B: Agriculture 1872-1914
    - Correspondence 1878-1914 (Box-folder 52-14-15)
    - Short-horn cattle pedigrees and registration forms 1872-1911 (Box-folder 52-16)
    - Farm reports 1887-1889 (Box-folder 52-17)
    - Farm account ledger 1909-1911 (Box-folder 52-18)
    - Speeches to agricultural organizations 1874-1878, n.d. (Box-folder 53-1-2)
    - Printed materials 1883-1909, n.d. (Box-folder 53-3)
    - Miscellaneous 1887, n.d. (Box-folder 53-4)
  - Subseries C: General Business and Personal Financial Papers 1862-1923
    - Correspondence
      - 1869-1923, n.d. (Box-folder 53-5-10)
    - Deeds and contracts 1874-1919 (Box-folder 53-11)
    - Money orders 1869-1899, n.d. (Box-folder 53-12)
    - Promissory notes 1867-1909, n.d. (Box-folder 53-13)
    - Legal papers 1873-1911, n.d. (Box-folder 53-14)
    - Receipts and account statements
      - 1866-1879 (Box-folder 53-15-17)
      - 1880-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 54-1-4)
    - Personal checks Bank of Christiansburg)
      - 1888-1891 (Box-folder 54-5-8)
    - Bank statements (Bank of Christiansburg) 1888-1891 (Box-folder 54-9)
    - Personal checks and bank statements (Bank of Pulaski) 1889-1890 (Box-folder 54-10)
    - Personal checks (Exchange Bank of Radford)
      - 1890-1893 (Box-folder 54-11-12)
    - Check stubs (Exchange Bank of Radford) 1892-1893 (Box-folder 54-13)
    - Personal checks (First National Bank of Radford)
      - 1919-1921 (Box-folder 54-14-15)
    - Check stubs (First National Bank of Radford) 1919-1921 (Box-folder 55-1)
    - Bank statements (First National Bank of Radford) 1920-1921 (Box-folder 55-2)
    - Personal checks (Lynchburg National Bank)
      - 1882-1885 (Box-folder 55-3-4)
    - Personal checks (National Exchange Bank of Lynchburg)
      - 1884-1887 (Box-folder 55-5-9)
    - Personal checks (Radford Trust Company) 1896 (Box-folder 55-10)
    - Bank accounts book 1879-1885 (Box-folder 55-11)
    - Home / farm / store ledger 1873-1890 (Box-folder 55-12)
    - Miscellaneous 1871-1921, n.d. (Box-folder 55-13)
- SERIES IV: EDWARD H. TYLER PAPERS 1877-1935
  - Outgoing correspondence 1879-1932, n.d. (Box-folder 56-1-2)
  - Incoming correspondence 1877-1911 (Box-folder 56-3)
  - Farm ledger 1884-1935, [also includes minutes of the Radford Rifles, 1892-1894] (Box-folder 56-4)
  - Accounts ledger 1889-1894 (Box-folder 56-5)
  - Financial papers 1900-1909 (Box-folder 56-6)
- SERIES V: J. HOGE TYLER JR. FAMILY PAPERS 1884-1926
  - Outgoing correspondence 1884-1908 (Box-folder 56-7-13)
  - Outgoing correspondence 1909-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 57-1-4)
  - Incoming correspondence 1897-1925, n.d. (Box-folder 57-5)
  - Evelyn Bell Tyler outoing correspondence 1911-1920, n.d. (Box-folder 57-6)
  - Pocket calendar 1914 (Box-folder 57-7)
  - Sigma Chi Quarterly Feb 1891 (Box-folder 57-8)
  - Sigma Chi quarterly Nov 1891 (Box-folder 57-9)
- SERIES VI: STOCKTON HETH TYLER FAMILY PAPERS 1885-1941
  - Subseries A: Personal Papers 1885-1941
    - Outgoing correspondence 1885-1916 (Box-folder 57-10-15)
    - Outgoing correspondence 1917-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 58-1-2)
    - Incoming correspondence 1896-1941 (Box-folder 58-3)
    - Nelle Serpell Tyler outgoing correspondence 1907-1936 (Box-folder 58-4)
    - Nelle Serpell Tyler outgoing correspondence n.d., [6 folders] (Box-folder 58-5)
    - Correspondence by other family members 1909-1923, n.d. (Box-folder 58-6)
    - Miscellaneous 1926-1935, n.d. (Box-folder 58-7)
  - Subseries B: Spanish-American War Records 1898-1899
    - Officers' mileage vouchers 1898-1899 (Box-folder 58-8-10)
    - Officers' pay and commutation vouchers 1898-1899 (Box-folder 59-1-3)
    - Officers' pay vouchers, A-M 1898-1899 (Box-folder 59-4-12)
    - Officers' pay vouchers, N-Z 1898-1899 (Box-folder 60-1-6)
    - Enlisted personnel final statements, A-K 1898-1899 (Box-folder 60-7-14)
    - Enlisted personnel final statements, L-Z 1898-1899 (Box-folder 61-1-6)
    - Enlisted personnel discharge vouchers 1898-1899 (Box-folder 61-7-15)
    - Company payrolls 1898-1899
      - 1st Alabama Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 62-1)
      - 1st Florida Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 62-2)
      - 2nd Illinois Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 62-3)
      - 4th Illinois Infantry (Box-folder 62-4)
      - 160th Indiana Infantry (detachment of sick) (Box-folder 62-5)
      - 21st Kansas Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 62-6)
      - 31st Michigan Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-1)
      - 14th Minnesota Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 63-2)
      - 1st Mississippi Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-3)
      - 2nd Mississippi Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-4)
      - 8th New York Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 63-5)
      - 69th New York Infantry, [5 folders] (Box-folder 63-6)
      - 1st Ohio Cavalry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-7)
      - 4th Ohio Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-8)
      - 6th Ohio Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 63-9)
      - 1st Pennsylvania Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 64-1)
      - 2nd South Carolina Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 64-2)
      - 4th Tennessee Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 64-3)
      - 2nd Texas Infantry (Box-folder 64-4)
      - 4th Virginia Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 64-5)
      - 1st Wisconsin Infantry (Box-folder 64-6)
      - 6th U. S. Cavaly (detachment) (Box-folder 65-1)
      - 7th U. S. Cavalry (detachment) (Box-folder 65-2)
      - 8th U. S. Cavalry (detachment) (Box-folder 65-3)
      - 2nd U. S. Engineers, [2 folders] (Box-folder 65-4)
      - 8th U. S. Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 65-5)
      - 15th U. S. Infantry, [2 folders] (Box-folder 65-6)
      - 21st U. S. Infantry (detachment) (Box-folder 65-7)
      - Ambulance Corps (Box-folder 65-8)
      - Hospital Corps (Box-folder 65-9)
      - Post Non-Commissioned Staff (Box-folder 65-10)
      - Signal Corps (Box-folder 65-11)
    - Abstracts of collections 1898-1899 (Box-folder 65-12)
    - Abstracts of mileage payments 1898-1899 (Box-folder 65-13)
    - Abstracts of payments Jul-Dec 1898 (Box-folder 65-14-15)
    - Account current statements 1898-1899 (Box-folder 65-16)
    - Analysis of disbursements 1898 (Box-folder 65-17)
    - Appropriations receipts 1898-1899 (Box-folder 65-18)
    - Fund transfer vouchers 1898-1899 (Box-folder 66-1)
    - Paymaster's clerk mileage vouchers (W. H. Hale) 1898-1899 (Box-folder 66-2)
    - Disbursing officers' check books 1898-1899 (Box-folder 66-3-5)
    - Statement of public funds book 1898-1899 (Box-folder 66-6)
    - Correspondence / communications 1898-1899 (Box-folder 66-7-9)
    - Special orders from the United States Adjutant General's Office Jul-Oct 1898 (Box-folder 66-10-12)
    - Special orders from the United States Adjutant General's Office Nov-Dec 1898 (Box-folder 67-1-2)
    - Special orders from the United States Adjutant General's Office Jan-May 1899 (Box-folder 67-3-6)
    - Index to special orders issued from the United States Adjutant General's Office 1898 (Box-folder 67-7)
    - General orders from the United States Adjutant General's Office Jan-Apr 1899 (Box-folder 67-8)
    - Printed materials 1898 (Box-folder 67-9)
      - Compendium of general orders from the United States Adjutant General's Office, amending army regulations since their publication... 1898
      - General orders and circulars, the United States Adjutant General's Office 1898
      - Manual for the pay department... 1898
    - Printed materials 1899, n.d. (Box-folder 67-10)
      - Appendix to army regulations... 1899
      - Examination paper: administration, United States Army regulations n.d.
      - "Monthly station list of the officers of the Pay Department, United States Army" Apr 1899
      - "Monthly station list of the officers of the Pay Department, United States Army" May 1899
    - Miscellaneous 1898-1899, n.d. (Box-folder 67-11)
- SERIES VII: BELLE TYLER MCCONNELL FAMILY PAPERS 1889-1954
  - Belle Tyler McConnell outgoing correspondence 1889-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 68-1-12)
  - Belle Tyler McConnell incoming correspondence 1901-1928, n.d.
    - A-H (Box-folder 68-13-14)
    - I-Z, Unidentified (Box-folder 69-1-2)
  - Frank P. McConnell outgoing correspondence 1908-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 69-3-6)
  - Frank P. McConnell incoming correspondence 1891-1926, n.d.
    - A-J (Box-folder 69-7-15)
    - K-Z, Unidentified (Box-folder 70-1-12)
  - Receipts and account statements 1909-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 70-13-17)
  - Legal papers 1900-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 70-18)
  - Personal financial records 1912-1924, n.d. (Box-folder 70-19)
  - Bank reports and financial statements 1911-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 70-20)
  - Bank and business records 1911-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 71-1-2)
  - Virginia Trust Company checkbook 1921-1922 (Box-folder 71-3)
  - Kappa Alpha fraternity purser's reports 1911-1912 (Box-folder 71-4-6)
  - Kappa Alpha travel vouchers 1911 (Box-folder 71-7)
  - Kappa Alpha Journal (Box-folder 71-8)
    - May 1922
    - Nov 1924
  - Invitations and programs 1902-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 71-9)
  - Printed materials 1898-1926, n.d. (Box-folder 71-10-13)
  - Miscellaneous 1904-1927, n.d. (Box-folder 71-14)
- SERIES VIII: SUE TYLER JOPLING FAMILY PAPERS 1896-1940
  - Outgoing correspondence 1896-1916 (Box-folder 71-15-18)
  - Outgoing correspondence 1917-1940, n.d. (Box-folder 72-1-8)
  - Incoming correspondence 1905-1925, n.d. (Box-folder 72-9)
  - Robert W. Jopling outgoing correspondence 1915-1925 (Box-folder 72-10)
  - Miscellaneous 1902, n.d. (Box-folder 72-11)
- SERIES IX: HAL C. TYLER PAPERS 1886-1940
  - Outgoing correspondence 1900-1940, n.d. (Box-folder 72-12)
  - Incoming correspondence 1902-1930, n.d.
    - A-I (Box-folder 72-13-15)
    - J-Z, Unidentified (Box-folder 73-1-3)
  - Southwest Virginia Agricultural and Live Stock Fair Sep-Oct 1902, n.d. (Box-folder 73-4-5)
  - Promissory notes 1886-1935 (Box-folder 73-6)
  - Legal documents 1906-1938, n.d. (Box-folder 73-7)
  - Financial papers 1908-1940 (Box-folder 73-8)
  - Miscellaneous 1900-1911, n.d. (Box-folder 73-9)
- SERIES X: LILY TYLER WILSON FAMILY PAPERS 1889-1956
  - Subseries A: Henry H. and Lily Tyler Wilson Papers 1889-1954
    - Lily Tyler Wilson outgoing correspondence 1889-1916 (Box-folder 73-10-13)
    - Lily Tyler Wilson outgoing correpondence 1917-1954, n.d. (Box-folder 74-1-7)
    - Lily Tyler Wilson incoming correspondence 1889-1942, n.d. (Box-folder 75-1)
    - Diary 1909 (Box-folder 75-2)
    - "Poems by Lily Tyler" [typescript] n.d. (Box-folder 75-3)
    - Theatre scrapbook 1898-1921 (Box-folder 75-4)
    - Scrapbook 1908-1915 (Box-folder 75-5)
    - Dance cards (Virginia Tech) 1904-1908 (Box-folder 75-6-7)
    - Dance cards (non-Virginia Tech) 1901-1910 (Box-folder 75-8)
    - Legal papers 1886-1935, n.d. (Box-folder 75-9)
    - Henry H. Wilson papers 1902-1933, n.d. (Box-folder 75-10)
    - Genealogy 1906-1932, n.d. (Box-folder 75-11)
    - Construction industry printed materials 1921-1932 (Box-folder 75-12-14)
    - Construction industry printed materials 1933 (Box-folder 76-1)
    - Other printed materials 1915-1949 (Box-folder 76-2)
    - Miscellaneous 1884-1931, n.d. (Box-folder 76-3)
  - Subseries B: James Hoge Tyler Wilson Papers 1918-1950
    - Printed material 1936-1943, n.d. (Box-folder 76-4)
    - Miscellaneous 1918-1950, n.d. (Box-folder 76-5)
  - Subseries C: Lily Norwood Wilson Papers 1924-1956
    - Outgoing correspondence 1926-1951, n.d. (Box-folder 76-6)
    - Incoming correspondence 1924-1956, n.d. (Box-folder 76-7-9)
    - Baby book 1919 (Box-folder 76-10)
    - School memorabilia 1930-1937, n.d. (Box-folder 76-11-12)
    - Calling cards and invitations 1924-1939, n.d. (Box-folder 76-13)
    - Event programs 1934-1939, n.d. (Box-folder 76-14)
    - European tour memorabilia 1935-1936, n.d., [see also Box 77, Folder 1] (Box-folder 76-15)
    - European tour memorabilia 1935-1936, n.d., [see also Box 76, Folder 15] (Box-folder 77-1)
    - British War Relief Society memoranda 1941 (Box-folder 77-2)
    - British War Relief Society Emblem Committee 1941, n.d. (Box-folder 77-3-4)
    - British War Relief Society miscellaneous 1941, n.d. (Box-folder 77-5)
    - Miscellaneous 1934-1938, n.d. (Box-folder 77-6)
- SERIES XI: HAMMET FAMILY PAPERS 1832-1913
  - Subseries A: William H. Hammet Papers 1832-1878
    - Papers 1832-1869, n.d. (Box-folder 77-7)
    - Physician's acount book 1836-1851, [also includes J. Hoge Tyler ledger entries, 1881-1885] (Box-folder 77-8)
  - Subseries B: Edward Hammet Papers 1832-1892
    - Lammermoor plantation records 1866-1872, n.d., [see also Box 78, Folders 4 and 5] (Box-folder 77-9)
    - Personal papers 1832-1871, n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 77-10)
    - Estate [J. Hoge Tyler, executor] 1851-1892, n.d. (Box-folder 78-1)
  - Subseries C: James P. Hammet Papers 1856-1879
    - Correspondence 1864-1878, n.d. (Box-folder 78-2)
    - Pocket diaries 1866-1873, n.d. (Box-folder 78-3)
    - Lammermoor plantation ledger 1857-1863 (Box-folder 78-4)
    - Aldomar and Lammermoor plantations account book 1867-1868 (Box-folder 78-5)
    - Plantation accounts with freedmen 1866-1868, n.d. (Box-folder 78-6)
    - Bills of lading 1866-1875, n.d. (Box-folder 78-7)
    - Receipts and account statements 1856-1879, n.d. (Box-folder 78-8-11)
    - Promissory notes and money orders 1856-1877, n.d. (Box-folder 78-12)
    - Legal papers 1866-1879 (Box-folder 78-13)
    - Physician's account book 1855-1860, [also includes J. Hoge Tyler day book entries, 1879-1881] (Box-folder 79-1)
    - Physician's account and log book 1854-1878, [also includes farm accounts, estate inventory, etc.] (Box-folder 79-2)
    - Patient accounts 1867-1876, n.d. (Box-folder 79-3)
    - Insurance 1866-1874 (Box-folder 79-4)
    - Miscellaneous 1866-1868, n.d. (Box-folder 79-5)
  - Subseries D: Isabella Hammet Heth Family Papers 1861-1913
    - Isabella Hammet Heth correspondence 1861-1913, n.d. (Box-folder 79-6)
    - Stockton Heth correspondence 1867-1913, n.d. (Box-folder 79-7)
- SERIES XII: SIFFORD FAMILY PAPERS 1805-1886
  - George W. H. Sifford personal correspondence 1860-1886, n.d. (Box-folder 79-8)
  - George W. H. Sifford receipts and account statements 1836-1885, n.d. (Box-folder 79-9-12)
  - George W. H. Sifford legal papers 1838-1883 (Box-folder 79-13)
  - Samuel Sifford papers 1840-1860, n.d. (Box-folder 79-14)
  - Miscellaneous 1805-1883 (Box-folder 79-15)
- SERIES XIII: PHOTOGRAPHS 1890-1939
  - J. Hoge Tyler portraits
    - Studio portraits [photos 001-007] n.d., [see also Oversize Materials] (Box-folder 80-1)
      J. Hoge Tyler [002] (jpg)
      J. Hoge Tyler [003] (jpg)
      J. Hoge Tyler [004] (jpg)
      J. Hoge Tyler [006] (jpg)
  - J. Hoge Tyler snapshots (Box-folder 80-2)
    - With J. Hoge Tyler II and J. Hoge Tyler III [photo 008] n.d.
    - With family [photo 009] n.d.
      J. Hoge Tyler Family [009] (jpg)
    - Seated on bleachers [photos 010-011] n.d.
    - With unidentified woman [photo 012] n.d.
      J. Hoge Tyler [012] (jpg)
    - On boat [photo 013] n.d.
    - On train platform, addressing troops [photo 014] n.d.
    - Eating with members of the Virginia Volunteers [photo 015] n.d.
    - With carriage [photo 016] n.d.
    - With William Jennings Bryan and others [photo 017] n.d.
      J. Hoge Tyler [017] (jpg)
  - J. Hoge Tyler snapshots (Box-folder 80-3)
    - With others at home of Steven and Lucy Nickeron Wilson (Lexington, Missouri) [photo 018] n.d.
    - With William Jennings Bryan and others at Halwick [photo 019] n.d., [2 copies]
    - With others in home draped with bunting [photo 020] n.d.
  - J. Hoge Tyler snapshots (Box-folder 80-4)
    - J. Hoge Tyler monument (Richard W. Bock, sculptor) [photos 021-032] 1937
  - J. Hoge Tyler Jr. (Box-folder 80-5)
    - Hampden-Sidney College sophomore English class [photo 033] 1891
    - Sigma Sigma chapter of Sigma Chi fraternity (J. Hoge Tyler II believed to be in third row, second from left, standing) [photo 034] [1890]
  - Hal C. Tyler (Box-folder 80-6)
    - [Hal C. Tyler][photo 035] [1933], [see also Oversize Materials]
    - [Hal C. Tyler] [photo 036] n.d., [3 copies]
    - [Hal C. Tyler] with unidentified young man [photo 037] n.d., [2 copies]
  - Lily Tyler Wilson family
    - Henry H. Wilson studio portraits (Box-folder 80-7)
      - Henry H. Wilson in V.P.I. cadet uniform [photo 038] c.1906, [3 copies]
        Henry H. Wilson [038]
      - Henry H. Wilson [photo 039] n.d.
        Henry H. Wilson [039]
    - J. Hoge Tyler Wilson (Box-folder 80-8)
      - J. Hoge Tyler Wilson [photo 040] 1931